# Saurabh Singh

saurabhurajput@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/developersaurabhsingh/ | Kitchener, Ontario | 226-899-0143

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 4 years of experience designing, evaluating, and developing software solutions. In-depth understanding of web technologies with focus on delivering innovative business solutions. Excels in fast-paced, high-energy, and deadline-driven environment with willingness to take on additional tasks.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

AlphaKOR Group Windsor, Ontario Software Engineer 12/2022 – Present

- Implemented a cross-cutting layer code and libraries suite, optimizing developer efficiency by reducing code duplication and improving maintainability across multiple projects. Increased team productivity by 40%.
- Developed and executed a robust training program, instructing 5 employees on best practices for software utilization, leading to a 25% increase in overall productivity and a 15% reduction in error rates.
- Optimized and enhanced the performance and usability of the system by about 4x.
- Successfully delivered before schedule, reducing report access time by 30%.
- Leading development to optimize task management and reduce response time by 40%.

## **Gateway Group of Companies**

Ahmedabad, Gujarat

08/2020 - 04/2022

Software Engineer

- Created a 3-layer grid system using Angular same as Data-table from scratch.
- Improved code quality and reduced technical debt by writing comprehensive unit tests, consistently maintaining over 90% code coverage.
- Built reusable components and services that improved code efficiency by 20%.
- Increased the code reusability by 30% in the module to plug-and-play components in Angular.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to design and implement features, resulting in a 30% user engagement.
- Created custom dashboards and data visualizations using D3.js and Highcharts.js, improving data insights and decision-making capabilities by 50%.

Surat, Gujarat **Android Developer** 

- 01/2018 08/2020Tenacious Techies Maintained mobile applications resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement and a 30% increase in app
- Actively participated in code reviews, offering constructive feedback, and following agile development methodologies.
- Collaborated with designers and product managers to implement pixel-perfect user interfaces.
- Employed debugging and profiling tools to identify and address performance bottlenecks.
- Leveraged Java and Kotlin to write clean, efficient, and maintainable code that adheres to industry best practices.

# **EDUCATION**

Conestoga College Kitchener, Ontario 05/2022 - 08/2023 Web Development

**Charotar University of Science and Technology** 

Anand, Gujarat Master of Computer Application 07/2019 - 06/2021

Naran Lala College Kitchener, Ontario Bachelor of Computer Application 07/2015 - 06/2018

#### CERTICATION

- Azure Fundamental Certificate
- NPTEL's Programming in Java

#### **SKILLS**

Tools: Visual Studio, VS Code, GitHub, Microsoft Azure, Jira, DevOps, Docker, Kubernetes, APIs, CI/CD, REST Framework & Library: Angular, ASP.net Core, React.js, Node.js, SQL Server, Android, Microservices, Web Programming languages: C#, Python, JavaScript, C++, Java, Ajax, GraphQL, Redux.js, PHP, Html, CSS, SaaS